ivytech.edu 2019-03-27

# Privacy - Ivy Tech Community College of Indiana

##### General

Ivy Tech Community College of Indiana respects the privacy of every individual who visits our site. This Privacy Policy outlines the information the Ivy Tech website may collect and how we may use that information. Ivy Tech reserves the right to alter this policy at any time by posting a new privacy policy at this location.

##### **Definition**

The "Ivy Tech website" is defined as publicly accessible pages hosted under the domain www.ivytech.edu.

The Ivy Tech website may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that Ivy Tech is not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites. This policy applies solely to information collected by this website.

##### **Personal Data**

We will not collect any personally identifiable information about you, such as name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address ("personal data") through our site unless you have provided it to us voluntarily. If you do not want your personal data collected, please do not submit it to us.

When you do provide us with personal data, we may use that information in the following ways, unless stated otherwise: we may process that information in order to fulfill an order or request you have placed with us; we may store and process that information to better understand your needs and how we can improve our products and services; we (or a fulfillment house or other third party on our behalf in connection with a promotion) may use that information to contact you; and/or we may provide other third parties with aggregate - but not individual - information about visitors to or users of our site. We will not sell, rent, or market personal data about you to third parties.

##### **Children/Direct Notice To Parents**

The Ivy Tech website has no intention of collecting any personal data from individuals under 13 years of age without parental consent. Where appropriate, we will specifically instruct those under thirteen not to submit such information on our site and/or will take reasonable steps to ensure parental consent to such submission.

##### **Additional Information Collected Automatically**

In some cases, we may automatically (i.e. not via registration) collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the type of Internet Browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, the IP address of your computer, and the domain name of the website from which you linked to our site. This information is used to ensure our site meets the needs of the majority of our users, as well as to diagnose problems with our server. This information also helps us produce statistics on how often our various pages are visited.

##### **Information Placed Automatically on Your Computer/Cookies**

When you view our site, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a "cookie" or similar file and can help us in many ways. For example, cookies allow us to tailor a website to better match your interests and preferences. With most Internet Browsers, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all Cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your Browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions.

##### **Public Forums**

This site may make message boards available for public use. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information.

##### **Security and Privacy Expectations**

The Ivy Tech website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via our site, this information is encrypted and remains secure during all stages of transmission. The Ivy Tech website complies with all State and Federal statutes requiring safeguards on specific types of information. However, due to the rapidly evolving nature of information technologies, no transmission of information over the internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. While Ivy Tech is committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors, the College cannot guarantee the security of any information visitors transmit to College sites, and visitors do so at their own risk.

##### **E-mail**

If you no longer wish to receive emails, you can click on the link at the bottom of the email message to unsubscribe, or call 888-IVY-LINE and request to be removed from future emails.

##### Student Rights

Ivy Tech Community College recognizes its responsibility to support and uphold the basic freedoms and citizenship rights of all students.

In the Code of Student Rights and Responsibilities, the term “student” is used to refer to a currently enrolled student, a prospective student, or a group of currently enrolled and/or prospective students. Furthermore, a student who discontinues enrollment after allegedly violating the Code of Student Rights and Responsibilities shall be considered a student for the purposes of the conduct proceedings until such matter is resolved.

Within the context of the entire educational setting this includes experiences both inside and outside the classroom. All students have the following rights as listed on the Code of Student Rights and Responsibilities page.

##### Student Records/FERPA

Ivy Tech maintains an educational record for each student who is or has been enrolled at Ivy Tech. In accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, the student rights that are listed on our FERPA page are covered by the act and afforded to all students at Ivy Tech.

##### Concerns/More Information

Please contact us with any concerns or questions. E-mail [helpdesk@ivytech.edu](mailto:helpdesk@ivytech.edu), or contact us via postal mail at:

Communications and Marketing Division  
Ivy Tech Community College  
50 W. Fall Creek Parkway North Drive  
Indianapolis, IN 46208-5752
